My most recent business just surpassed 3
million US dollars in just over a
year and a half. I don't do sales calls.
I don't really have a massive team.
I don't have to market it very hard.
I put out maybe two videos a week.
I haven't written an email,
marketing email, for this in months.
It's good,
but it's made up of five revenue streams,
which I'm not sure everyone is
aware of. So in this video,
I'm going to go through them because I
think some of
you could take inspiration from this
and apply this to your business,
whatever it
is. So there's a nice number.
I sometimes look at that and go, "Where
is it?" Some
of it's there, granted.
It's not 3 million in my bank.
My manager gets a cut, team get a cut.
We've got paid ads to cover,
and then the taxman.
So there's technically 20 different
products, and I've blurred them.
Not to be Machiavellian,
there's just some people that
are coming through on old
offers.
They might have found a link from several
months ago, and I don't want
people that have just joined to feel like
I'm doing them dirty.
But the pie chart I want to look to on the
left. June, 209,000 US dollars.
Not bad.
Now if we go down here,
you'll notice the pie chart
is done on revenue.
But don't let that fool you,
because Content Mastery here, which
is a $99 course
that teaches people how to make short-form
content, of which there's going to be a
link in the description. Even though
that doesn't look like much of the pie
chart,
we sold 320 units.
That's 10 people a day are buying that.
The Email Advantage, we revamped.
That one, again, link in the description,
$99.
That's more to someone
that they know they should be doing email
marketing, but
they haven't. This slither here
is a bundle that we took offline.
People are still getting it.
Then we have a PT Starter Kit.
One of my videos has just taken off
randomly. Let me show you, actually.
See, I've been away for the weekend.
I proposed to my partner,
so she's now my fiancée.
If you notice, some views
are cranking in from old videos.
So you see this one here? This
is why I love YouTube. January 7th,
long time ago.
Last 48 hours, 1,000 views.
So you see here, for some reason, I
have no idea, I wish I could tell you,
"hummm" just took off.
And because of that,
and the fact I've got tracking links,
this video is just
making sales. That's the reason YouTube
is great,
because you can sometimes just have a
video that you've barely touched in ages,
and
it just takes off,
and it just gets you views for whatever
reason.
So as you can see,
8% of this month's revenue has come from
an old
video that randomly took off.
Then the Business Mentorship here,
where I coach
people who have small businesses,
69% of the revenue. Here's the play.
Why would you sell a $99 course? Well,
not everyone is ready to hand over 3,000
US
dollars. So what I want to do
is give them a taste.
And for $99, I actually over-deliver.
I give them more than $99 worth of value,
so that when they buy and they have that
first transaction, they go, "Wow,
actually,
that was really good." Then even better
yet, say someone goes away
and uses Email Advantage
or Short Form Content Mastery.
Within maybe two, three, four weeks,
it could attribute to one, two,
three sales.
And they go, "Wow, okay. I paid James.
I learnt a skill. I implemented the skill.
I made money from it." They pay the extra
money to actually get access to me.
Those $99 courses,
although they make you a bit of the pie,
they actually bring
people into the ecosystem. Of
which some go,
"Thank you for the advice," and
they're gone.
But other people will upsell.
We're about 10, 11% at the moment,
and we are off the mark.
This is actually last week's business
plan.
And what we do each week
is we not only look at the revenue that's
being attributed
from different revenue streams,
we then look at the videos to see how many
clicks
they're attributing to the lead magnets.
More importantly, the conversions,
whether or not some of those videos
are just
cranking sales. Like this one is unreal.
And I won't lie,
I'd have nothing to talk about,
nothing to make a video about.
Went online, saw Iman Gadzhi
was having an outlier, took the thumbnail,
took the
title, never watched the video,
made my own, but better.
Now again here,
we can have a look at a snapshot of the
revenue of the different
products. April was big, granted.
And you'll see a little fuck-up
that I made here.
February,
I took a whole month off posting.
I went back to the UK, had a month off.
I actually rewrote the entire Business
Mentorship.
March, we came back with a vengeance.
Now, for an anchoring point,
I just wanted the Mentorship to look
cheaper when we
put the price up.
I opened some one-to-one coaching.
It's a $10,000 offer.
It went to $12,500 straight away.
I sold too many of them, to the point that
I took it offline. And even then,
we sold a few more in April.
I said, "Guys,
please stop selling this."
And although April was a fantastic month,
now I'm just not doing one-to-one.
It's exhausting because
when you pay someone $1,500 to sit on a
call,
you don't just sit on a call with them,
"Oh, Dave, how's it going?" You have to be
on the ball, and it's exhausting.
And to be honest,
I'd rather have those hours to
myself to make videos like this to market
the business.
It's why I don't like people doing sales
calls. It's too much energy.
The reason, and $1,500 an hour.
I can wake up, do two
calls before 9:00 a.m.
That call's paid off for the week.
Other call's paid off for the week.
All the groceries paid off for the week,
and the mortgage is paid off for the week.
I was like, "No,
I'd rather make content." Anyway,
so we can see trends.
We can look at things. For instance,
the one-to-one coaching thing,
which I took
offline.
And the $1 Fundamentals course
that we put in here, didn't get the
effect we wanted from it,
so we just took it offline.
And it still makes some sales,
but not enough to sing home about.
Then another thing that we said before
is not always to look at the amount of
revenue that someone's making
and take it as face value.
As you can see here,
we spent $50,000 in June.
Granted, we made 71,000 back,
and we get a return on ad spend, a ROAS,
of
1.5, which is down on the month before.
But it is quite cool
that every $100 you would spend,
you would make one and a half
dollars. So again,
you make 200K for the month.
Straight away, take 47 off for ads.
And some people can think, "Oh,
that's really expensive."
But keep in mind that for
some of these people, where these ads,
we spent the money and we didn't get the
response or the sale that we wanted,
it's exposure.
Maybe this month we don't attribute it to
a sale, but next month they finally
crack.
And it might've been all the ads they saw
before that makes them eventually
make the sale.
So I don't get too sad looking at this
because all the people that
didn't buy, it's free exposure.
Then here you can see some of the email
automations and what they're doing.
So I don't write these emails.
These have already been pre-written.
Again,
I teach all of this in the Email
Advantage, link in the description.
But you can see this month alone,
the revenue is just churning in from those
lead magnets that I put out. Again,
even if you look at the description to
this
video, you'll see all the paid stuff.
Then underneath, there's the free stuff.
Again,
the majority of these clicks have come
through from YouTube videos where I
tell people to check out the description.
They find their way through.
Oh, here's the Discord I
was saying before.
So whatever channel you go to,
you will just see me, me,
me. My head is pretty much everywhere.
Every single person,
whatever they want to ask,
we get back into it.
We get into it. And again,
I know some people would very much like to
do
one-to-one and do hours on calls.
But the truth is,
I can spend an hour in here.
After this video that I'm recording,
I spend an hour here.
I chat to people,
and it's not too-Too intensive
or draining on me.
And if my missus needs me upstairs to help
change a nappy, I can go up, I can come
back down.
If for whatever reason today's a bit
hectic and I jump in at 8:00 PM,
cool. When there's calls in my diary,
I hate it.
The whole day is kind of ruined trying to
make up for that call.
We've actually got a really good thread in
here at the moment talking about trial
reels and some of the impacts we're
getting and not getting with it. Anyway.
I feel I can give people more
and charge them a lot less using a
platform like
Discord. And it also means
that sometimes you might have a burning
question in your
mind, "Oh, I'm thinking of doing this.
Do you think it's a good idea?"
And saying no to that could save you days,
weeks,
months, or saying yes to
that can just give you the confidence to
launch it.
So back to the point of the revenue
streams and sometimes the smaller
products.
I hate the word low ticket.
I hate it because so many creators out
there in their
businesses think, "Oh,
I'll just create a shit offer,
something crap, and I
will just get 1,000 people to buy it
and I'll make 1,000 times a small
amount of money." Instead of thinking
that, I think of it this way.
Think about satellite products
that can be specific to something.
I actually, in the next few weeks,
I'm going to start branching out some more
$99
products in various different niches,
one of which I'm going to build just
around
teaching people how their bio on Instagram
should look.
Small course, charge maybe, I don't know,
$49, whatever.
These satellite courses
are going to be great because I'm going to
give them to my
existing clients for free.
They're going to log in one day and go,
"Wow, there's
more resources." To people
that haven't bought my stuff yet,
I'm going to put them
all around the internet
and make videos that will then people
going towards them.
Then probably 10, 11,
12% of those people will upgrade into the
business
mentorship. This serves three things.
Firstly,
it serves my existing clients by giving
them updated and new
stuff that they don't pay extra for.
It serves also a big demographic of people
that don't want access to me and don't
want to spend thousands of dollars.
They just want the one thing,
and they can go away.
And the third thing
is it just gives people
that ability to have a little taster
before they get into it,
because a lot of people
that do what I do online are shit.
They don't know what they're doing.
They tell people to DM people once they
just start following them.
They tell them to hang out in Facebook
groups.
They tell them to run free challenges for
people. It's just dog shit advice.
Get them on a sales call.
Don't reveal your pricing. It's shithouse.
So for those of you that
are working out there hammering your main
offer, I'm not
saying to abandon that.
I'm not saying go low ticket.
I'm saying,
is there one component of your business,
maybe a repeated question that
your clients ask you
or the people you work with ask you?
Could you build something smaller,
standalone,
that doesn't take any of your time
and effort?
And can we plant it out there as a
satellite course?
We can then create content
that sends people to
that course where nine out of 10 of
them go, "Cheers. Thank you. That
was great." They can go,
and one out of 10 of
them will find their way into your main
offer. It's pretty good.
And if you can apply
that into your own business,
you'll do great.
Now, if you are a personal trainer
and you want to know why this video has
taken
off and why so many people are buying
that PT bundle starter kit, well, you can
click here and watch it,
but I would advise only watching it
if you're a personal
trainer. But saying that,
some of you other ones,
you could watch it if you're not.
That's it.